<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>OctoPrint</title>
 <link href="http://foosel.github.com/OctoPrint/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://foosel.github.com/OctoPrint"/>
 <updated>2013-03-31T17:05:44+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://foosel.github.com/OctoPrint</id>
 <author>
   <name>Gina Haeussge</name>
   <email>osd@foosel.net</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Progress report</title>
   <link href="http://foosel.github.com/OctoPrint/blog/2013/03/18/progress-report"/>
   <updated>2013-03-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://foosel.github.com/OctoPrint/blog/2013/03/18/progress-report</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Weekly update regarding development progress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most labor intensive change this week(end) is that OctoPrint now &amp;#8211; after intense debugging across the pond with &lt;a href='https://github.com/daftscience'&gt;Tom Perry&lt;/a&gt; &amp;#8211; supports the Repetier firmware. In order for this to work I had to overhaul major parts of the communication layer inherited from Cura, including the resend mechanism, but it finally resulted in a success. The outcome of this &amp;#8211; among some new gray hairs &amp;#8211; were two new configuration settings, &amp;#8220;Send a checksum with every command&amp;#8221; and &amp;#8220;Send M110 commands with target line number as N-prefix&amp;#8221; in the feature tab, that you&amp;#8217;ll have to tick in order to be able to print on a Repetier enabled printer. For now the code will only be available in the &lt;a href='https://github.com/foosel/OctoPrint/tree/repetier'&gt;&amp;#8220;repetier&amp;#8221; branch&lt;/a&gt; as I want to test the overhauled communcation a bit more with Marlin (you are btw welcome to help here!) before I merge it into devel and after that into master, but it&amp;#8217;s looking promising.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;As yesterday&amp;#8217;s mini update suggested, I also added a new logfile &lt;code&gt;terminal.log&lt;/code&gt; which logs the serial communication that so far only available in the terminal tab. Due to performance reasons you&amp;#8217;ll have to supply the &lt;code&gt;--debug&lt;/code&gt; command switch on OctoPrint&amp;#8217;s startup to enable this.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='https://github.com/daprice'&gt;Dale Price&lt;/a&gt; sent a pull request fixing an iOS Bug that caused control buttons only working once (due to iOS caching the POST request&amp;#8230; I don&amp;#8217;t even&amp;#8230;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Raspberry Pi setup guide and configuration documentation got moved to the &lt;a href='https://github.com/foosel/OctoPrint/wiki'&gt;wiki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I also fixed a couple of small things along the way (that I&amp;#8217;m completely unable to recall right now)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No screenshots today, since all of this stuff was only in the backend. Maybe Tom Perry will give me permission to post a shot of his very special whiteboard though, to make up for it ;)&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>